Guide to the Jennie Warner Papers MS 025
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Jennie Warner Papers
1908-1917
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Warner, Jennie Esther.
MS 025
0.75 Linear Feet, 2 boxes
Jennie Esther Warner graduated from Danbury Normal School in 1917. The collection includes some of her texts and notebooks from her time at the DNS and Danbury High School.
Provenance
Provenance is unknown.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Jennie Esther Warner graduated from Danbury Normal School in 1917. A lifelong resident of Danbury, Connecticut, she married Frank M. Stone between 1916 and 1923. The couple had at least one child, a son, Frank M. Stone, Jr. Both father and son worked at the family business, The Stone Company, Inc., a local hardware and painting/decorating store.
Jennie lived at 15 Abbott Avenue for her entire married life. While attending DNS, during 1916, Jennie boarded at 15 Ellsworth Avenue. This address was owned by one of her relatives, Theodore O. Warner, Jr.
Sources:
Danbury/Bethel City Directories, 1923, 1916, 1936, 1948, 1915, 1972, 1984.
WCSU Alumni Directory, 1984.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection contains materials from Jennie's high school and college days. Several issues of Danbury High School's literary journal/yearbook are included. The rest of the collection is made up of materials from Jennie's two years at DNS. Of particular interest are her student notebooks from various classes. Also included are science, history, and algebra texts. The science textbook, Elementary Science, was authored by Lothrop D. Higgins, the second principal of the college. He started out here as a science teacher.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
Inventory.
Notebooks.; Notes; School yearbooks.; Textbooks.; Danbury (Conn.); Danbury Normal School.; Stone, Frank M., Jr.; Warner, Jennie Esther.; Warner, Theodore O., Jr.
- Inventory
  - Danbury High School Chronicle, 1910-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Student Notebook: Art (fragile), 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Notebook: Art of Teaching, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Notebook: Bible Study, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Student Notebook: Chemistry II, Div. 1A (2 notebooks), 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Student Notebook: Civics, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student Notebook: Gymnasium 1A, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Notebook: Laboratory 1A, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Notebook: Language, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student Notebook: Literature 1A, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Student Notebook: Literature and Language 2A, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Student Notebook: Memory Gems, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Student Notebook: Music, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Student Notebook: Word Puzzles, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Textbook: Elementary Science, Lothrop D. Higgins (Danbury, CT: Normal School, 1914) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Textbook: Essentials of American History and Civics, Harriet Hoffman McLaury (Brooklyn, NY: T. J. McEvoy, 1911) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Textbook: Houston's Writing Lessons, Harry Houston (New Haven, CT: 1901) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Textbook: Modern Illustrative Bookkeeping, E. Virgil Neal (New York, NY: American Book Company, 1901) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Textbook: Standard Algebra, William J. Milne (New York: American Book Company, 1908) (fragile) (Box 2, Folder 5)